Finding Aid for the Collection of 19th-century European Sheet Music, circa 1791-1900
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Collection of 19th-century European Sheet Music, circa 1791-1900
Mus. Arc. 48
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
3 linear feet ( 4 boxes, 149 items )
Collection of 125 complete pieces of sheet music from European countries: Austria (5), Belgium (6), England (54), France (9), Germany (31), Italy (14), and the Netherlands (5). Most of these include title page illustrations, about 30 of which are in color. The collection includes an additional 24 partial works, most of which consist only of their title pages. The musical content consists of 44 works for solo piano and approximately 75 works for some combination of voice and piano.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Collection compiled by the Music Library from a combination of purchases and gifts.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Historical Note
The collection was compiled by staff of the University at Buffalo Music Library, drawing on both gifts and purchased acquisitions.
Scope and Content Note
Collection of 125 complete pieces of sheet music from European countries: Austria (5), Belgium (6), England (54), France (9), Germany (31), Italy (14), and the Netherlands (5). Most of these include title page illustrations, about 30 of which are in color. The collection includes an additional 24 partial works, most of which consist only of their title pages. The musical content consists of 44 works for solo piano and approximately 75 works for some combination of voice and piano. Overall, the collection provides a representative sample of sheet music publishing practices in European markets during the 19th century as well as lithographic art and some of the extra-musical topics treated as subjects for music during the period. Very few of the works bear copyright or publisher dates. As a result, dates have been supplied from various sources or estimated.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
I. Complete works
II. Partial works
Container List
- Complete works, circa 1791-1900, I.; Items 1-125
  Arranged alphabetically by surname of composer and then by preferred title of the composition.
  - Abt, Franz, 1819-1885 Lieder, op. 39. No. 1-2 Agathe - Irene: zwei Lieder aus dem Buch der Liebe, 1846, 1 score (7 pages); Stuttgart (Germany): Karl Göpel For voice and piano. Lyricist: Herlosssohn, C. (Carl), 1804-1849 Title page notes "Ausgabe für Sopran oder Tenor". English translation of text for Agathe by John Henry Gordon; for Irene by E.A. Moriarty. Bound together with "Der Alpengruss Schweizerlied" by Adolf Hofmeister. Orpheon, Album fur Gesang mit Pianoforte, no. 28 and no. 47. (Box 1, Item 001)
  - Adams, Stephen, 1844-1913 Nancy Lee waltz; arranged Nancy Lee waltz, between 1875 and 1880, 1 score (8 pages); London (England): Boosey and Co. For piano. Arranger: Löffler, Fred Color title page illustration: a ship at sea / lithographed by Stannard and Son. (Box 1, Item 002)
  - Adams, Thomas, 1785-1858 Melross Abbey Melross Abbey: a Scotish [sic] divertimento, circa 1815, 1 score (8 pages); London (England): G. Walker For piano. Title page illustration: a view of the Melross Abbey. (Box 1, Item 003)
  - Albert, Charles d', 1809-1886 Edinburgh quadrille Edinburgh quadrille: upon Scotch airs, 1852, 1 score (9 pages); London (England): Chappell For piano. Color title page illustration: Highland soldiers in red uniforms overlooking the city of Edinburgh from the top of Edinburgh Castle. (Box 1, Item 004)
    No. 1. Pantalon. The MacGregor's march; Jenny put the kettle on -- No. 2. Ètè. Annie Laurie -- No. 3. Poule. Kinloch of Kinloch; Ye banks and braes o' Bonnie Doon -- No. 4. Trenise. My love is like the red, red rose -- No. 5. Finale. Hazeldean; Maggie Lauder; The blue bells of Scotland.
  - Albert, Charles d', 1809-1886 National Schottisch National Schottisch, circa 1850, 1 score (6 pages); London (England): Chappell For piano. First page notes "not to be played so fast as the polka". Color title page illustration: green leaves and a brown wooden border surrounding the title / lithographed by Ford and George. (Box 1, Item 005)
  - Albert, Charles d', 1809-1886 Queen of roses Queen of roses: valse, circa 1860, 1 score (9 pages); London (England): Chappell and Co. For piano. Title page illustration: portrait of a young woman holding flowers, with flowers also in her hair and in a basket at her side. (Box 1, Item 006)
  - Albert, Charles d', 1809-1886 Reaper's polka Reapers: polka, 1858, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Chappell and Co. For piano. Color title page illustration: two children in dresses with flowers in their hair picking produce and harvesting wheat. / M and N. Hanhart, Imp. (Box 1, Item 007)
  - Albert, Charles d', 1809-1886 Sardinian polka Sardinian polka, circa 1860, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Chappell and Co. For piano. Library copy trimmed, missing bottom portion of title page. Color title page illustration: portrait of Victor Emanuel II in military uniform on a white horse. (Box 1, Item 008)
  - Auber, D. F. E. (Daniel François Esprit), 1782-1871 Muette de Portici. Amis, la matinée est belle; arranged Morn breaks all beautiful and bright: the celebrated barcarolle in Auber's opera of Masaniello: Performing at the Theatre Royal Drury Lane, adapted to English words by Richard Ryan and arranged for the piano forte by John Barnett, 1828, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Goulding and D'Almaine For voice and piano. Lyricist: Ryan, Richard, 1796-1849 Arranger: Barnett, John, 1802-1890 Other title: Morn breaks Title page illustration: portrait of three characters and their actors from the opera, Moreno (Mr. Yarnold), Masaniello (Mr. Braham), and Ruffino (Mr. Bland) with people dancing in the background / drawn by J.W. Gear; lithographed by W. Day. (Box 1, Item 009)
  - Auber, D. F. E. (Daniel François Esprit), 1782-1871 Muette de Portici. Selections; arranged Six of the most favorite airs from Auber's celebrated opera of Masaniello, circa 1835, 1 score (13 pages); London (England): G. Shade For piano. Arranger: Smith, H. Color title page illustration: people in blue dress fighting one another with axes at a marketplace. (Box 1, Item 010)
    The Market Chorus -- Triumphal March -- The Barcarolle -- The Tarantella -- The Guaracha -- The Fishermen's Chorus.
  - Banck, Carl, 1809-1889 Fahrt nach Sicilien Fahrt nach Sicilien: Lied, circa 1836, 1 score (3 pages); Leipzig (Germany): F. Hofmeister For voice and piano. "Lithorama no. 9". Title page illustration: several men on a boat accompanied by two dolphins and another boat. (Box 1, Item 011)
  - Banck, Carl, 1809-1889 Matrosenabschied Matrosenabschied: Lied, circa 1836, 1 score (3 pages); Leipzig (Germany): F. Hofmeister For voice and piano. "Lithorama no. 3". Title page illustration: a person paddling a boat with two boats in the background. (Box 1, Item 012)
  - Blamphin, Charles, -1895 Death of Stonewall Jackson Stonewall Jackson: recitative and air, 1865, 1 score (9 pages); London (England): Brewer and Co. For voice and piano. 5th edition. Title page illustration: a portrait of Stonewall Jackson in military uniform / J. Brandard; M. and N. Hanhart, Imp. (Box 1, Item 013)
  - Blockley, John Jessie's dream Jessie's dream: a story of the "Relief of lucknow", between 1861 and 1863, 1 score (7 pages); London (England): John Blockley For voice and piano. Lyricist: Campbell, Grace Score preceded by an excerpt "from a letter written by M. de Banneroi, a French physician in the service of Mussur Rajah, and published in Le Pays (Paris paper), dated Calcutta, Oct. 8/[18]57." Title page illustration: two women sitting on a decrepit wooden structure speaking with one another, with soldiers in background. Captioned: Dinna ye hear it, dinna ye hear it? (Box 1, Item 014)
  - Blockley, T. Just as I am Just as I am: sacred song, 1863, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Addison and Co. For voice and piano. "Inscribed to The Revd. Norman Macleod, D. D."--Caption title. Title page illustration: a male figure, accompanied by a broken sword, dice, and coins, kneeling at prayer beneath a crown of thorns and a lamb / A. Laby. (Box 1, Item 015)
    First page contains text to the first verse of music written as a poem.
  - Blockley, T. Sun of my soul Sun of my soul, 1863, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): John Blockley For voice and piano. Lyricist: Keble, John, 1792-1866 Title page illustration: Jesus Christ standing in front of a cross in the clouds / A. Laby. (Box 1, Item 016)
    Title page contains text to the first verse of music written as a poem.
  - Bohlman-Sauzeau, Henri Palais enchanté Palais enchanté: quadrille caracteristique, 1855, 1 score (7 pages); London (England): D'Almaine and Co. For piano. Title page illustration: a couple through a window or mirror at another couple in the distance / E. Noyce; lithographed by Stannard and Co. (Box 1, Item 017)
    1. Pantalon: Arrivée du Chevalier maudit -- 1. Ètè: Serments d'amour -- 3. Poule: La chasse infernale -- 4. Pastourelle: Bal au Palais enchanté -- 5. L'enfer.
  - Campana, F. (Fabio), 1819-1882 Bella Lituana Souvenir del lago di Como: melodie italiane: La bella Lituana: duettino, 1871, 1 score (9 pages); Milan (Italy): Edizioni ricordi For soprano and contralto, with piano and chorus ad libitum. Dedicated to Miss Iarvis and Miss Louisa Iarvis [Jarvis?]. Title page illustration: filigree illuminating title. (Box 1, Item 018)
  - Campana, F. (Fabio), 1819-1882 Potenza d'amore Alla moda: album vocale: Potenza d'amore: duetto, 1856, 1 score (7 pages); Milan (Italy): G. Ricordi For soprano and contralto, with piano. Lyricist: Pepoli, Carlo, conte, 1796-1881 Title page illustration: filigree with sheets of music illuminating title. (Box 1, Item 019)
  - Campana, F. (Fabio), 1819-1882 Povero Tonio! Sospiri d'Italia: album per canto: Povero Tonio!: duettino comico, 1868, 1 score (8 pages); Milan (Italy): G. Ricordi For soprano and bass with piano. Dedicated to Mrs. Brook. Title page illustration: filigree illuminating title. (Box 1, Item 020)
  - Campana, F. (Fabio), 1819-1882 Speranza Canzoni Napoletane: Omaggio a Venezia album per canto: La speranza: duettino, 1867, 1 score (9 pages); Milan (Italy): G. Ricordi For two voices and piano. Dedicated to Maggior William Palliser and Capitano Wrav Palliser. Title page illustration: people dancing with mountains in the background. (Box 1, Item 021)
  - Carulli, Gustavo, 1801-1876 Ètoile chèrie Dilettante: Ètoile chèrie: romance, 1842, 1 score (3 pages); Brussels (Belgium): J. E. Libau For voice and piano. Lyricist: Barateau, Émile Other title: Dilettante. No. 30 Title page erroneously spells composer's last name as "Corulli". Title page illustration: a man sitting on a rocky outcropping underneath a tree looking over a lake. (Box 1, Item 022)
    Additional verses notated without music on the final page.
  - Clapisson, L. (Louis), 1808-1866 Je ne suis qu'une femme! Dilettante: je ne suis qu'une femme!: romance, 1842, 1 score (3 pages); Brussels (Belgium): J. E. Libau For voice and piano. Lyricist: Humbert, Auguste Other title: Dilettante. No. 28 Title page illustration: a man and a woman sitting on a couch holding hands. A dog with a bird in its mouth sits at their feet. (Box 1, Item 023)
  - David, Félicien, 1810-1876 Fleurs d'été Fleurs d'été: trois valses expresives, 1846, 1 score (7 pages); Mainz (Germany): B. Schott For piano. Distributed by J. Meifsonnier and Fils, Paris. Color title page illustration: flowers in bright colors illuminating title. (Box 1, Item 024)
    No. 1. Souvenir -- No. 2. Babillage -- No. 3. L'aveu.
  - Davie Occasional collection of popular dances. No. 33 Davie's occasional collection of popular dances: arranged for the piano forte, harp, or violin, with proper figures: No. 33, circa 1813, 1 score (4 pages); London (England): Bland and Weller's Music Warehouse For piano. Title page illustration: people dancing outside a house. (Box 1, Item 025)
    Harlequin hoax (the rondo in the overture) / Parry -- The Isle of Elba -- Calder fair -- Dennis O'Larry / Parry -- National blunders -- Mrs. George Dering's waltz -- Fair cheating (from the Overture) / Parry -- The Lily of Limmington -- The Corsair.
  - Delaseurie, Arthur Polka des demoiselles Polka des demoiselles, 1864, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Robert Cocks and Co. For piano. Title page illustration: a woman playing piano and other women dancing in pairs / Stannard and Dixon, Imp. (Box 1, Item 026)
  - Dorn, Edouard, 1838-1923 Murmure du Ruisseau Murmure de Ruisseau: caprice, op. 44, circa 1870, 1 score (11 pages); Offenbach am Main (Germany): Jean André For piano. Color title page illustration: woodland stream with a mill in the background and two people on a bridge overlooking the scene. (Box 1, Item 027)
  - Fahrbach, Philipp, 1815-1885 Pepita polka Pepita-polka, op. 152, 1857, 1 score (5 pages); Vienna (Austria): C. A. Spina For piano. Title page illustration: portrait of Pepita de Oliva (Josefa Durán y Ortega) dancing, with castanets in hands. (Box 1, Item 028)
  - Faust, Carl, 1825-1892 Früh am Morgen Früh 'am Morgen: Marsch, op. 311, 1879, 1 score (5 pages); Breslau (Germany): Julius Hainauer For piano. Color title page illustration: a couple with supplies in traditional dress walking down a path. (Box 1, Item 029)
  - Faust, Carl, 1825-1892 Jubiläums Marsch Jubiläums Marsch: op. 108, 1863, 1 score (5 pages); Breslau (Germany): Julius Hainauer For piano. Composed for "dem Königlichen Musìk-Director Herrn W. Wieprecht". Dates on title page: 17 Maerz 1813 and 18 Octb. 1813 refer to the German Campaign against Napoleon. Title page illustration: portraits of King Friedrich William III of Prussia and Queen Louise of Mecklenburg-Strelitz above vignettes of two men on battle horses with a filigree border. (Box 1, Item 030)
  - Gernlein, Rudolph Morgenständchen Morgenständchen: "Sei mein du Liebchen rosenroth", circa 1828, 1 score (5 pages); Berlin (Germany): Bechtold and Hartje For voice, with piano or guitar. Lyricist: Gerhard, Wilhelm, 1780-1858 Includes separate guitar line. (Box 1, Item 031)
  - Giorza, Paolo, 1832-1914 Conte di Monte Cristo. Galopp; arranged Galoppo: nel ballo il Conte di Monte Cristo, circa 1860, 1 score (4 pages); Naples (Italy): Carteria e copisteria di musica For piano. Reduced for piano. Color title page illustration: filigree border surrounding hand-written title text. (Box 1, Item 032)
  - Glover, Stephen, 1813-1870 My father's hand My father's hand: sacred song, circa 1868, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): C. Jefferys For voice and piano. Lyricist: Marian At head of title: Noonday song. Color title page illustration: an angel dropping flowers bordered by gold filigree / M. and N. Hanhart. (Box 2, Item 033)
  - Glover, Stephen, 1813-1870 National divertimentos, no. 2 National divertimentos, no. 2: Ireland, circa 1840, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Jefferys and Nelson For piano. Other title: Picturesque divertimentos, no. 2 Caption title. Title page title is Picturesque divertimentos. Color title page illustration: people launching a sailboat on the Lake of Killarney in Ireland bordered by gold filigree / J. Brandard; lithographed by M. and N. Hanhart. (Box 2, Item 034)
    [Fanfare] -- Savoureen deelish -- Rory O'More.
  - Glover, Stephen, 1813-1870 Osborne quadrilles Osborne quadrilles, circa 1850, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Robert Cocks and Co. For piano. "Composed in honor of the birth-day of Her Royal Highness, The Princess Royal". Color title page illustration: portrait of the Princess Royal (Victoria Adelaide Mary Louisa) sitting on a red pillow / lithographed by Stannard and Dixon. (Box 2, Item 035)
  - Glover, Stephen, 1813-1870 Prince Albert's march Prince Albert band march: Ninety-ninth thousand, circa 1860, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): C. Jefferys For piano. Other title: Prince Albert's band march Title page illustration: a portrait of Prince Albert in military uniform on horseback / lithographed by R. Brandon and So. (Box 2, Item 036)
  - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 Faust. Si le bonheur à sourire t'invite; arranged L'Age d'or: Collection chant et piano. A une sœur, circa 1859, 1 score (5 pages); Paris (France): Choudens Fils For voice and piano. Lyricist: Pradère, O. Other title: A une sœur Each page is bordered by a filigree frame. Title page illustration: a vignette of a castle overlooking a waterfall and filigree illuminating title. (Box 2, Item 037)
  - Grisar, Albert, 1808-1869 Bonsoir, Monsieur Pantalon. Selections; arranged Bonsoir, Mr. Pantalon!: polka, 1853, 1 score (3 pages); Mainz (Germany): B. Schott For piano. Arranger: Pasdeloup, Jules, 1819-1887 Piece is a piano arrangement of a theme from the opera Bonsoir, Mr. Pantalon! by Alfred Grisar. Title page illustration: a man with a sorrowful look carrying three bottles. (Box 2, Item 038)
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 Messiah. But thou didst not leave his soul in hell; arranged But thou didst not leave from the Mesiah [sic], circa 1821, 1 score (3 pages); London (England): G. Walker For voice and piano. Interlinear text. (Box 2, Item 039)
  - Handl, Jacob, 1550-1591 O salutaris hostia O salutaris hostia = O gnadenreiche Glaubenskraft, circa 1840, 1 score (4 pages); Berlin (Germany): Ed. Bote and G. Bock For four-part choir. Other title: Musica sacra, Tomus quintus. No. 15 Caption title. Title page notes "zum bestimmten Gebrauch fur den Königlichen Berliner Domchor" [for specific use by the Royal Berlin Domchor]. (Box 2, Item 040)
  - Hart, Joseph Binns, 1794-1844 Royal gallopades and waltzes, 1st set Royal gallopades: as danced at His Majesty's Grand ball, 1829, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Mayhew and Co. For piano. Other title: Hart's First set of gallopades First page notes "the Music of the Gallopades is so arranged by Mr. Hart that the figures of his celebrated Quadrilles, The Lancers, 7.10.13 and indeed all his Sets may be introduced with good effect. See engraving on the title page.". Title page illustration: couples dancing in a ballroom / printed by Engelmann, Graf, Coindet and Co. (Box 2, Item 041)
    Gallopades no. 1-5.
  - Hartog, Édouard de, 1825-1909 Avril Avril: chant de printemps, circa 1852, 1 score (3 pages); Paris (France): Au Ménestrel For voice and piano. Lyricist: Constantin, Marc, 1809?-1888 Other title: Esquisses pastorales :Mars et Avril Interlinear text. Caption title. Dedicated to Mlle. Léonie de Mergy. Title page illustration: floral filigree illuminating title / lithographed by A. Barbizet. (Box 2, Item 042)
  - Hauptmann, Lorenz Geheime Thräne Geheime Thräne: Lied, circa 1860, 1 score (7 pages); Vienna (Austria): F. Gloggl For voice and piano. Componist und dem Herrn Ignate Küss Beamter der oesterreichischen Nationalbank". (Box 2, Item 043)
  - Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809 Schöpfung. Mit Würd' und Hoheit angetan; arranged In native worth and honor clad: a favorite air sung by Mr. Nield in the oratorio of The Creation, 1820, 1 score (3 pages); London (England): G. Walker For voice and piano. (Box 2, Item 044)
  - Hayes, Sarah Ann Princesses of England Princesses of England: waltzes, circa 1854, 1 score (16 pages); London (England): T. C. Bates and Son For piano. Color title page illustration: portraits of the five princesses of England captioned with their names / lithographed by J. Brandard. (Box 2, Item 045)
    Invitation -- Princess Royal -- Princess Alice -- Princess Helena -- Princess Louisa.
  - Heinze, Gustav Adolph, 1821-1904 Veilchen Veilchen: Lied, 1850, 1 score (6 pages); Amsterdam (Netherlands): Theune and Co. For voice and piano. Title page notes this is a for "Alt- oder Bariton-Stimme". Title page notes "komponist und seine Schülerin Fräulein Louise Bunge" [composed and dedicated to his student Fräulein Louise Bunge]. (Box 2, Item 046)
  - Heiser, Wilhelm, 1816-1897 Musik Musik: op. 6: Gedicht von Helene, Herzogin von Orleans, circa 1890, 1 score (7 pages); Berlin (Germany): C. A. Challier and Co. For voice and piano. Lyricist: Orléans, Hélène d', Princess of France, 1871-1951 Title page illustration: filigree with a cherub at the bottom illuminating the title. (Box 2, Item 047)
    First page contains text of poem by itself.
  - Henrion, Paul Ah! Je suis ben embarrassé! Ah! Je suis ben embarrassé!: chansonnette, 1845, 1 score (3 pages); Brussels (Belgium): J. E. Libau For voice and piano. Lyricist: Sauvage, Elie, 1814-1871 Other title: Lemonde musical On title page: Lemonde musical. No. 21. Title page illustration: two women outside of a small house / Singelis. (Box 2, Item 048)
  - Henrion, Paul Ne pars point, mon fils! Ne pars point, mon fils!: romance, 1843, 1 score (3 pages); Brussels (Belgium): J. E. Libau For voice and piano. Lyricist: Barateau, Émile Other title: Lemonde musical On title page: Lemonde musical. No. 25. Title page illustration: a man and a woman outside of a small house with a church steeple in the background / Singelis. (Box 2, Item 049)
  - Hérold, Ferdinand, 1791-1833 Clochette. Selections; arranged Clochette, ou Le diable-page: couplets chantés par Madame Boulanger, 1817, 1 score (4 pages); Hague (Netherlands): F. J. Weygand For voice and piano. Lyricist: Théaulon, Emmanuel, 1787-1841 At head of title: No. 4. (Box 2, Item 050)
    Pages bound out of order. Additional verses notated without music on the final page.
  - Hérold, Ferdinand, 1791-1833 Pré aux clercs. À la fleur du bel âge; arranged Pré aux clercs: ronde chantée par Melle. Massi [À la fleur du bel âge], 1833, 1 score (3 pages); Hague (Netherlands): F. J. Weygand For voice and piano. Music notes the voice part is for the role of Nicette. At head of title: No. 8. (Box 2, Item 051)
  - Hérold, Ferdinand, 1791-1833 Pré aux clercs. Souvenirs du jeune âge; arranged Souvenir du jeune âge: romance le l'opera Pré aux clercs, 1834, 1 score (3 pages); Hague (Netherlands): F. L. Dony For voice and piano. Music notes the voice part is for the role of Isabelle. Title page notes this is a for "la même avec accompt. de guitare". 3rd edition. (Box 2, Item 052)
    Additional verses notated without music on the final page. Alternate ornamental ending notated on final page.
  - Holst, M. (Matthias), 1767-1854 Julia's cottage Julia's cottage: march and rondo, 1811, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Bland and Weller's Music Warehouse For piano. Title page illustration: a cottage with a small shed / lithographed Jones Scrips. (Box 2, Item 053)
  - Hurka, Friedrich Franz, 1762-1805 Maedchen an ihren Geliebten Maedchen an ihren Geliebten: eine Antwort auf Overbecks Schiffahrt, circa 1800, 1 score (3 pages); Hamburg (Germany): Joh. Aug. Böhme For voice and piano. Lyricist: Werder, Friedrich, 1783-1858 (Box 2, Item 054)
  - Hurka, Friedrich Franz, 1762-1805 Saenger Saenger, circa 1800, 1 score (3 pages); Hamburg (Germany): Joh. Aug. Böhme For voice and piano. Lyricist: Becker (Box 2, Item 055)
  - Ingle, Charles Our little nipper Our little nipper: humorous song, 1892, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Reynolds and Co. For voice and piano. Lyricist: Chevalier, Albert, 1861-1923 "Dedicated to Colin Grattan Esq, (aged 5)". Title page illustration: various vignettes of a little boy with several captions / Henderson and Spalding, Limtd. (Box 2, Item 056)